A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1936-1996. (Box 62)
  - Writings., See also Roberta Wohlstetter File
    - Manuscript for unpublished book with possible title, "Council Book," or "War by Mistake,", 1964-1966
      - Background materials (Folder 162: 10)
      - Correspondence (Folder 162: 11)
      - Notes (Folder 162: 12)
      - Outline (Folder 162: 13)
      - Typescript (Folder 162: 14)
      - Typescript (Box 163)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 164: 1-3)
      - Reviews (Folder 164: 4)
    - "Dealing with Castro's Cuba" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1965 January 16. (Folder 164: 5)
    - "Making 'Apocalyptic Views' More Precise,", 1965 March 25. (Folder 164: 6)
    - Controlling the Risks in Cuba (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1965
      - Background materials (Folder 164: 7)
      - Correspondence. (Folder 164: 8)
        Includes requests to reprint and use the materials
      - Notes (Folder 164: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 164: 10)
      - Printed copy of version in Adelphi Papers, 1965 April (Folder 164: 11)
    - "Does 'The Horrid Possibility' of Nuclear Sabotage Make Defense against Nth Country Attack Useless?", 1965 June 6. (Folder 164: 12)
    - "Rationality and the Prisoner's Dilemma,", 1965 June 15. (Folder 164: 13)
    - "The Freeze and Non-Members,", 1965 July 2. (Folder 164: 14)
    - "Ballistic Missile Defense and 'Asian Hostages to China',", 1965 July 19 (Box 165)
      - Background materials (Folder 165: 1)
      - Notes (Folder 165: 2)
      - Typescript (Folder 165: 3)
    - "Alternatives to Nuclear Weapons for an Adversary's Pressure on a Small Neighbor,", 1965 July 23. (Folder 165: 4)
    - "The Costs of Entering the Nuclear Club,", 1965 July 24
      - Notes (Folder 165: 5)
      - Typescript (Folder 165: 6)
    - "Setting Reasonable Limits to the Chinese Threat,", 1965 July 25. (Folder 165: 7)
    - "Comments on Leon Sloss's TN SSC-TN-11: BMD and Arms Control,", 1965 July 27. (Folder 165: 8)
    - "Rationale of the Over-All Chinese Communist Nuclear Threat,", 1965 July 30. (Folder 165: 9)
    - "Comments on A.C.D.R.U. Paper,", 1965 August 19. (Folder 165: 10)
    - "United Europe's Supposed Need for Nuclear Weapons to Be Sovereign,", 1965 August 23. (Folder 165: 11)
    - "The Question of Bypassing BMD through Nuclear Sabotage,", 1965 August 26. (Folder 165: 12)
    - "Interwar and Postwar Concepts of 'Defense' and Interadversary Agreements,", 1965 August 27. (Folder 165: 13)
    - "Limiting Damage and Binomial Probabilities,", 1965 November 2. (Folder 165: 14)
    - "Madness and Statemen,", 1965 November 23. (Folder 165: 15)
    - "Israel,", 1966
      - General (Folder 165: 16)
      - Background materials (Folder 165: 17)
      - Correspondence (Folder 165: 18)
      - Notes (Folder 165: 19)
      - Typescript (Folder 165: 20)
    - "The Non-Strategic and the Non-Existent,", 1966
      - Background materials (Folder 165: 21)
      - Correspondence (Folder 165: 22)
      - Notes (Folder 165: 23)
      - Typescript (Folder 165: 24)
      - Printed copy (Folder 165: 25)
    - "Defense and Stability,", 1966 January (Box 166)
      - Background materials (Folder 166: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 166: 2)
    - "Non-Alignment, the Two Bandungs, and Communist Aggression,", 1966 January 17. (Folder 166: 3)
    - "Stability among Many Nations and Preclusive First Strike Capability,", 1966 February 3. (Folder 166: 4)
    - "Triggering Deterrent,", 1966 February 10. (Folder 166: 5)
    - "Timing of Chinese Nuclear Development, U.S. Ballistic Missile Defense, and Nth Country?", 1966 March 8. (Folder 166: 6)
    - "Atoms for Equality,", 1966 March 10
      - Typescript (Folder 166: 7)
      - Review (Folder 166: 8)
    - Article re the importance of fulfilling the United States commitments to Europe and other countries as a means of maintaining peace, Foreign Affairs, 1966 April
      - Notes (Folder 166: 9)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 166: 10-11)
    - "Comments on the Kaiser Engineers Catalyctic Corporation Report on Desalting,", 1966 June 16. (Folder 166: 12)
    - "Near Zero Probability of War on Europe and the 'Disarmers',", 1966 July 5. (Folder 166: 13)
    - "Costs and Attrition: Realities versus Quick Computation,", 1966 September 15-16
      - Background materials (Folder 166: 14)
      - Notes (Folder 166: 15)
      - Typescript (Folder 166: 16)
    - "Value and Factual Statements, and C. G. Hampel,", 1966 December 4. (Folder 166: 17)
    - "Myths of Economic Regionalism and the Art of Long and Short Hauls,", 1966 December 5
      - Background materials (Folder 166: 18)
      - Typescript (Folder 166: 19)
    - "Technology, Capabilities and Interests in the 1970's,", 1967? (Folder 166: 20)
    - "Diverging Series of Predictions About 1967 Soviet Union ICBMs and the Converging 'Missile Gap' Predictions," (Folder 166: 21)
    - "Fulbright on the Inevitability of War,", 1967 January 8
      - Typescript (Folder 166: 22)
      - Review (Folder 166: 23)
    - "A Cost Ineffectiveness Handbook,", 1967 January 10. (Folder 166: 24)
    - "Theory and Opposed-Systems Design," Journal of Conflict Resolution, 1968. (Folder 166: 25)
    - "Illusions of Distance,", 1968 January (Box 167)
      - Correspondence (Folder 167: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 167: 2)
      - Printed copies
        - Foreign Affairs (Folder 167: 3)
        - Tsushin, 1968 December? (Folder 167: 4)
    - "Black Power: Its Problems, Its Rival Factions, and Its Strategies,", 1968 February
      - Background materials (Folder 167: 5)
      - Notes (Folder 167: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 167: 7)
    - "Two Motivations for U.S. Sponsorship of Regionalism,", 1968 February 3. (Folder 167: 8)
    - "Perspective on Nuclear Energy," Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1968 April
      - Correspondence (Folder 167: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 167: 10)
      - Galley (Folder 167: 11)
      - Printed copy (Folder 167: 12)
    - "On Vietnam and Bureaucracy,", 1968 July 17. (Folder 167: 13)
    - "Equal Condition versus Compensated Equal Opportunity,", 1968 August 3
      - Background materials (Folder 167: 14)
      - Typescript (Folder 167: 15)
    - "Metaphors and Models: Inequalities and Disorder at Home and Abroad" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1968 August 27. (Folder 167: 16)
    - "The Case for Strategic Force Defense," Why ABM?, 1969. (Folder 167: 17)
    - Comments on Abram Chayes and Jerome B. Wiesner, editors, ABM: An Evaluation of the Decision to Employ an Anti-Ballistic Missile System, 1969. (Folder 167: 18)
    - "SAFEGUARD: Compromise or Assured Waste in Kwajalein? The High Cost of Symbolism?" The Committee to Maintain a Prudent Defense Policy, 1969. (Folder 167: 19)
    - "Relying on Bombing Only and the Risks of War,", 1969 March 8. (Folder 167: 20)
    - "Do Defense Missiles Increase or Decrease Our Safety?", 1969 April 10
      - Background materials (Folder 167: 21)
      - Outline (Folder 167: 22)
      - Typescript (Folder 167: 23)
    - Open letter (with Dean Acheson and Paul Nitze) urging people to join the Committee to Maintain a Prudent Defense Policy, 1969 May 26 (Box 168)
      - General (Folder 168: 1)
      - Background materials (Folder 168: 2)
      - Correspondence (Folder 168: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 168: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 168: 5)
    - "Comments on the Basic Issues Paper,", 1969 June 8. (Folder 168: 6)
    - "Attacks on Radar,", 1969 July 6. (Folder 168: 7)
    - "Why Defense Against the Air-Breathing Threat?", 1969 July 6
      - Notes (Folder 168: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 168: 9)
    - "The Safeguard Program of Ballistic Missile Defense: How Well Will It Work?", 1969 July 11. (Folder 168: 10)
    - "An Analysis of Racial Disparities in Income: Summary,", 1969 September 24. (Folder 168: 11)
    - Comments on Michael Walzer, "The Revolution of the Saints: A Study in the Origin of Radical Politics,", 1969 November 11. (Folder 168: 12)
    - "Third Worlds Abroad and at Home" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), The Public Interest, 1969 Winter. (Folder 168: 13)
    - Race Differences in Income, 1970 February 11. (Folder 168: 14-15)
      Outline, typescript, and reprint
    - "Comments on Jackson Paper?", 1972
      - Background materials (Folder 168: 16)
      - Notes (Folder 168: 17)
    - "Marginal Comments on Greenwood Paper,", 1972
      - Memoranda (Folder 168: 18)
      - Typescript (Folder 168: 19)
    - "Mathematical Appendices from Wohlstetter/Coleman Paper,", 1972. (Box-folder 169: 1)
    - Untitled article on deterrence? (with Fred Hoffman), 1972 January 12. (Folder 169: 2)
    - "Outline on FCRCs,", 1972 March 21. (Folder 169: 3)
    - "Qualitative Competition and Qualitative Arms Races,", 1972 September. (Folder 169: 4)
    - Comments on Bellamy, "The Delicate Balance of Error: The Wohlstetter-Rathjens MIRV Controversy,", 1972 September 4. (Folder 169: 5)
    - "Comments on Desmond Ball Thesis,", 1972 October. (Folder 169: 6)
    - Comments on "Arms and Impotence: The Concepts of Violence, Rationality and Control in the Strategic Analyses of T. C. Schelling,", 1972 November
      - Correspondence. (Folder 169: 7)
        Albert Wohlstetter's letter to Marguerite Kramer, managing editor, Journal of Conflict Resolution
      - Typescript. (Folder 169: 8)
        May actually be a review of Davis and Schilling, "All You Ever Wanted to Know about MIRV and ICBM Calculations but Were Not Cleared to Ask"
    - "Apocalyptic Exaggeration, Maddox and Medawar,", 1972 November 12. (Folder 169: 9)
    - "Japan's Security: Balancing After the Shocks," Foreign Policy, 1972-1973 Winter. (Folder 169: 10)
    - "Competition or Race? Innovation and the Changing Size of Strategic Forces" (with A. Hoeber, Fred Hoffman, and D. McGarvey), 1973-1974.; See also Academic File
      - Background materials (Folder 169: 11)
      - Notes (Folder 169: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 169: 13-14)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 170: 1)
    - "Balancing After the Shocks," Foreign Policy, 1973 April 24. (Folder 170: 2)
      General
    - "The Two Problem Areas and Four Phases of the Research Efforts,", 1973 November 8. (Folder 170: 3)
    - Comments on "NATO's Northern Flank," 1973 November 10, on the RAND study by Fletcher, Olenikoff, and Van Dyke and on the comments by Klippenberg and Huitfeldt. (Folder 170: 4)
    - Comments for Newsweek on the article by John W. Finnet in the New York Times, 1974 January 23. (Folder 170: 5)
    - "Better Guidance, Pershing II and the Nuclear Threshold," 1974 January 25, comments on Michael Getler, "U.S. Eyes Miniature Warhead," Washington Post
      - Background materials (Folder 170: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 170: 7)
    - "Comments to Don Cotter on a Proposed Letter to the Senator on Improvements in Accuracy,", 1974 January 27. (Folder 170: 8)
    - "How Explain the Plateau in U.S. Strategic Budgets in 1955-1961 and the Turn Down?", 1974 April 6. (Folder 170: 9)
    - "Comments on Robert McNamara's Revision of History,", 1974 April 22. (Folder 170: 10)
    - "Comments on Sidney Drell's Paper 'SALT: Technological Impact on Progress and Prospects',", 1974 May 13. (Folder 170: 11)
    - "Cannikin,", 1974 May 15. (Folder 170: 12)
    - "Comments on Navwag Study November 1957 and Navwag July and October 1960,", 1974 May 23. (Folder 170: 13)
    - "The Apocalypse and the Nuclear Race: Renewal of Arms Race Doctrine in the 1940s,", 1974 June 2-3. (Folder 170: 14)
    - "AEC Proposal Phase I,", 1974 August 19. (Folder 170: 15)
    - "Stability in a World of Many Nuclear Powers,", 1974 August 27. (Folder 170: 16)
    - "National Security Implications of Technologies of Discrimination,", 1974 September 2. (Folder 170: 17)
    - "Rivals, but no Race," Foreign Policy, 1974 Fall. (Folder 170: 18)
    - "Diverging Series of Predictions about 1967 Soviet Union ICBMs and the Converging 'Missile Gap' Predictions,", 1974 December 1. (Folder 170: 19)
    - "Threats and Promises of Peace: Europe and America in the New Era," Orbis, 1974 Winter
      - Notes (Folder 170: 20)
      - Typescript (Folder 170: 21)
      - Printed copy (Box-folder 171: 1)
      - Translation into Japanese (Folder 171: 2)
    - "Reply to Nacht on Predictions,", 1975 January-March
      - Notes (Folder 171: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 171: 4)
    - "Slow or Rapid Initial Production of A-Bomb: Implications for Intelligence and Proliferation Policy,", 1975 February 2. (Folder 171: 5)
    - "Defining Policy on 'Non-Weapon States' and 'Peaceful Uses',", 1975 August 8. (Folder 171: 6)
    - "The Non-Proliferation Treaty and Main Incompatible Purposes of Treaty Makers,", 1975 August 20-24. (Folder 171: 7)
    - "Optimal Ways to Confusing Ourselves," Foreign Policy, 1975 Fall
      - General (Folder 171: 8)
      - Outline (Folder 171: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 171: 10)
      - Printed copy (Folder 171: 11)
    - "Relating Policy to the Problem of Critical Time That Is Shrinking Without Any Necessary Breaking of the Rules,", 1975 November 14
      - Background materials (Folder 171: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 171: 13)
    - Reply to Stone-Halperin paper, Foreign Policy, 1975 Winter. (Folder 171: 14)
    - "Varying Response with Circumstance in Europe" (with Henry S. Rowen), 1976 January. (Folder 171: 15)
    - "Comments on Things to Watch in Posture Statement,", 1976 January 21. (Box-folder 172: 1)
    - "Comments on the ACDA Draft on Reprocessing,", 1976 February 2. (Folder 172: 2)
    - "Political and Security Implications of the Spread of Civilian Nuclear Technologies,", 1976 May 4. (Folder 172: 3)
    - "Recycling, the Uranium 'Shortage' and the 'Energy Famine',", 1976 May 10
      - Background materials (Folder 172: 4)
      - Notes (Folder 172: 5)
      - Typescript (Folder 172: 6)
    - "U.S. Ambivalence and Recent Foreign Sales that Spread Bomb Technology,", 1976 May 11. (Folder 172: 7)
    - "South Africa and the Bomb: Internal Use by Government,", 1976 May 15. (Folder 172: 8)
    - "Racing Forward? Or Ambling Back?" SURVEY, 1976 Summer/Autumn. (Folder 172: 9)
      Printed copy. Includes printed copy published in Defending America, 1977
    - "How to Slow and Limit the Spread of Nuclear Weapons to More Countries,", 1976 September 14
      - Background materials (Folder 172: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 172: 11)
      - Translations
        - French (Folder 172: 12)
        - German (Folder 172: 13)
        - Swedish (Folder 172: 14)
    - "On Premature Commitments in Less Developed Countries,", 1976 September 22
      - Background materials (Folder 172: 15)
      - Typescript (Folder 172: 16)
    - "Basic Questions about the Gesmo,", 1976 October 22. (Folder 172: 17)
    - "An Answer to the 'So What' School" (with Harry Rowen)?, 1977. (Folder 172: 18)
    - "Eisenhower, Dulles, and Safeguards on Plutonium,", 1977 January 24. (Folder 172: 19)
    - "PRM-15," comments, 1977 February-March
      - Background materials (Folder 172: 20)
      - Outline (Folder 172: 21)
      - Typescript (Folder 172: 22)
    - "Civilian Noise, Response to Timely Military Signals, and the Influence of Incremental Costs, Incremental Time, and Incremental Risks on the Decision to Acquire Nuclear Weapons" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1977 August 20. (Folder 172: 23)
    - Untitled, 1977 August 23. (Folder 172: 24)
    - "Iran-Turkey Relations and the Ethnic Minority Problems,", 1977 September-October. (Folder 172: 25)
    - "The Military Potential of Civilian Nuclear Energy: Moving Towards Life in a Nuclear Armed Crowd?" Minerva, 1977 Autumn-Winter. (Box-folder 173: 1)
    - "NATO, Turkey and United States Interests," American Foreign Policy Institute, 1978. (Folder 173: 2)
    - Nuclear Policies: Fuel without the Bomb, 1978. (Folder 173: 3)
      Printed copy of review by Richard Norton
    - Article about the Middle East, 1978 April? (Folder 173: 4)
      Holograph of Elli Zeira's comments
    - "Comments on Vince Taylor's ACDA Article,", 1978 May 19. (Folder 173: 5)
    - "The Strategic Importance of Turkey and the Arms Embargo," Journal of International Relations, 1978 Summer. (Folder 173: 6)
    - Manuscript for projected book on "Power Projection", 1978-1980?
      - General (Folder 173: 7)
      - Background materials (Folder 173: 8)
      - Notes and outline (Folder 173: 9-10)
      - Typescript. (Box-folder 174: 1-2)
    - Swords from Plowshares: The Military Potential of Civilian Nuclear Energy, 1979
      - General (Folder 174: 3)
      - Background materials (Folder 174: 4)
      - Correspondence (Folder 174: 5)
      - Typescript (Folder 174: 6)
      - Printed copy (Folder 174: 7)
    - "Risks in Selling Uranium Futures and the Interdependent Economics of Plutonium and Uranium,", 1979 January 14
      - General (Folder 174: 8)
      - Correspondence (Folder 174: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 174: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 174: 11-12)
    - "Middle-East Instabilities and Distant Guarantors (And Disturbors) of the Peace: The Arab-Israeli Case" (with Richard Brody and Harry Rowen), 1979 March 29. (Folder 174: 13)
    - "Illustrative Options for U.S. and Allied Cooperation in Continuous Naval Deployments in the Indian Ocean/Arabian Sea,", 1979 June 15 (Box 175)
      - Background materials (Folder 175: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 175: 2)
    - "Latent Common Interests between Saudi Arabia/Kuwait and Turkey,", 1979 June 25. (Folder 175: 3)
    - "U.S. Non-Proliferation Strategy from Here On" (with Henry Rowen), 1979 August 29
      - Background materials (Folder 175: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 175: 5)
      - Review (Folder 175: 6)
    - "Nuclear Energy and an Ancient Indian View of Reality,", 1979 October 24. (Folder 175: 7)
    - Manuscript for projected book on Korea, 1980
      - Background materials (Folder 175: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 175: 9)
    - "Half-Wars and Half-Policies in the Persian Gulf,", 1980
      - General (Folder 175: 10-11)
      - Background materials (Box-folder 176: 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 176: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 176: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 176: 4-7)
      - Printed copy (Folder 176: 8)
    - "Defensive Expansion,", 1980 January 2 (Box 177)
      - Typescript (Folder 177: 1)
      - Galley (Folder 177: 2)
    - "Contingencies Studied (Persian Gulf),", 1980 January 14
      - Background materials (Folder 177: 3)
      - Outline (Folder 177: 4)
    - "Meeting the Threat in the Persian Gulf,", 1980 Spring
      - Background materials (Folder 177: 5)
      - Printed copy. Survey, 1981 April (Folder 177: 6)
    - "Note on Rob Silverstein's Points on the Navy and Power Projection,", 1980 May 9. (Folder 177: 7)
    - "Note on the Premises of Détente: Nuclear Superiority, Parity, and All That,", 1980 August
      - Notes (Folder 177: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 177: 9)
    - "Protecting Persian Gulf Oil: U.S. and Alliance Military Policy,", 1980 November. (Folder 177: 10-11)
    - "Threats from Inside the Region,", 1980 December 9. (Folder 177: 12)
    - Manuscript for projected book on Turkey, 1980-1984
      - Background materials (Folder 177: 13)
      - Background materials (Box-folder 178: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 178: 2)
    - Les États-Unis et la sécurité du golfe, 1981. (Folder 178: 3)
      Printed copy of version in Politique étrangère, 1981 January
    - "Power for Gulf Contingencies,", 1981 January 19. (Folder 178: 4)
    - "Thoughts on the Need for Precision for Attacks on Nth Country Nuclear Weapons Systems or Nuclear Facilities,", 1981 January 28. (Folder 178: 5)
    - "Meeting the Key Widely Separated Challenges of the 1980s: A New Alliance Strategy as a Context for Design of the Navy,", 1981 February 2
      - Background materials (Folder 178: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 178: 7-8)
    - "Virtual Wars, Worldwide Challenges and the Limits and Uses of Escalation,", 1981 February 3. (Folder 178: 9)
      Outline and related materials
    - "Threats Made Real by Doubt: Or, Self-Destroying Prophecies,", 1981 March 17. (Folder 178: 10)
    - "Biases in Comparing U.S.-S.U. Defense Budget Trends: The Volunteer Force,", 1981 March 18. (Folder 178: 11)
    - "The JCS in 1956 on the Importance of Turkish/NATO Forces for Middle East Contingencies,", 1981 April 10. (Folder 178: 12)
    - "Introducing Chemical Weapons without Insisting On European Stockpiling,", 1981 May 22
      - Notes (Folder 178: 13)
      - Typescript (Folder 178: 14)
    - "Virtual Wars and Interactions of Nuclear/Non Nuclear Threats in the European Center,", 1981 May 22
      - General (Folder 178: 15)
      - Typescript (Folder 178: 16)
    - Untitled outline, 1981 May 31. (Folder 178: 17)
    - "Superiority, Parity, and the Premises of Détente,", 1981 August. (Folder 178: 18-19)
    - "Turkey, NATO and Southwest Asia,", 1981 September 6. (Folder 178: 20)
    - Comments on Paul B. Henze's talk "Turkey, the Alliance and the Middle East: Problems and Opportunities in Historical Perspective,", 1982 January 19 (Box 179)
      - Notes (Folder 179: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 179: 2)
    - "Why We Should Declare the Polish Debt in Default,", 1982 February 3. (Folder 179: 3)
    - "George Ball's Hysteria about Calling in the Polish Loan,", 1982 February 15. (Folder 179: 4)
    - "Polish Credits and the Credibility of the Alliance,", 1982 March 18. (Folder 179: 5)
    - "Responses During and after the Missile Crisis,", 1982 April
      - Background materials (Folder 179: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 179: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 179: 8)
    - "Erosion of the Balance after the Cuban Missile Crisis,", 1982 April 10. (Folder 179: 9)
    - "Comments on 'Catalogue of Response Options: NATO',", 1982 Summer. (Folder 179: 10)
    - "That Would Mean World War III,", 1982 August 31. (Folder 179: 11)
    - "NATO after the Détente,", 1982 September 6
      - Background materials (Folder 179: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 179: 13)
    - "Nuclear Policies Clarified,", 1982 September-October. (Folder 179: 14)
      Typescript for Commentary
    - "The Soviet Threat,", 1982 December 3
      - Background materials (Folder 179: 15)
      - Typescript (Folder 179: 16)
    - "Preventing Nuclear War: Continuity and Continuing the Trend of Change,", 1982 December 17. (Folder 179: 17)
    - "Continuity in Nuclear Policy and Nuclear Change,", 1982 December 19. (Folder 179: 18)
    - "ACGA's Bulgarian Connection and the West's Aversion to Soviet Realities,", 1983. (Folder 179: 19)
    - "Just War Doctrines and the Discriminate and Proportionate Use of Nuclear Weapons,", 1983 January 7
      - Background materials (Folder 179: 20)
      - Typescript (Folder 179: 21)
    - "Warning – Cuban Missile Crisis,", 1983 January 11. (Folder 179: 22)
      Typescript. Includes notes by Roberta Wohlstetter and related materials
    - "Comments on Bundy, McNamara, Zumwalt,", 1983 March 9. (Folder 179: 23)
    - "The Second-Strike Theory of Deterrence: Origins, Meaning and Limits,", 1983 March 26. (Box-folder 180: 1-6)
    - "Thoughts after the President's Speech on Defense,", 1983 March 23. (Folder 180: 7)
    - "Reducing Whose Capability to Attack Whom?", 1983 April. (Folder 180: 8)
    - "We Need Nuclear-Viable Satellites for an Extended Non-Nuclear War,", 1983 April 9
      - Background materials (Folder 180: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 180: 10)
    - Bishops, Statesmen, and Other Strategists on the Bombing of Innocents, 1983
      - General (Folder 180: 11)
      - Background materials (Folder 180: 12)
      - Correspondence. (Folder 180: 13)
        Includes requests for permission to reprint
      - Notes (Box-folder 181: 1)
      - Typescript. (Folder 181: 2-6)
        Includes typewritten preface to the French edition, "Critique de la dissuasion pure," 1983 October-November
      - Printed copies, including version in Commentary, 1983 June (Folder 181: 7-8)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 182: 1)
      - Translations
        - French (Folder 182: 2)